# MICHAL RENTKA

Prague, Czech republic · +420 720 378 717 · michalrentka@gmail.com **LinkedIn · Portfolio** 

Results-oriented iOS developer with 7+ year experience in iOS development. I make it my goal to create iOS applications with the user in mind, creating applications with a useable and intuitive user interface experience. I also understand the importance of creating highly readable and easily maintainable source code. I am constantly striving to learn new technologies and look to ways to better myself in this rapidly changing industry.

## **EXPERIENCE**

**2019 - PRESENT** 

#### LEAD IOS DEVELOPER, CORPORATION FOR DIGITAL SCHOLARSHIP

Developer of the Zotero iOS app for iPhones and iPads.

2015 - 2019

### IOS DEVELOPER, SMSGRUPP

Developer of the **Supertext** messaging app. Responsible for development and maintenance. Performed complete app redesign within the first 6 months. Participated in an entire app rewrite, moving 90% of the project's code from Objective-C to Swift.

**2015 - PRESENT** 

## LEAD IOS DEVELOPER, OPOINT / M-BRAIN

Leading the iOS development of **Opoint** (now M360) and **M-Brain** apps. Participating in regular meetings with product managers and other developers. Architectured applications, codebase, dependencies, and build pipeline to support multiple developers. Developed customer facing features in an agile environment. Worked on short term prototypes for potential new functionality. Managed the release process to the iOS App Store.

2013 - 2015

#### IOS DEVELOPER, ENGAGE3

Involved in all stages of iOS development from architecture to coding to final testing. Responsible for definition, design, development and successful completion of major new features in products.

# **EDUCATION**

2012 - 2014

#### **MASTER'S DEGREE,**

MASARYK UNIVERSITY BRNO Degree in computer graphics and

Degree in computer graphics and image processing.

2009 - 2012

**BACHELOR'S DEGREE,** 

MASARYK UNIVERSITY BRNO

Degree in computer graphics.

# **SKILLS**

- Swift
- Objective-C
- UI & UX design
- Testing
- Deployment
- CI
- GIT
- Javascript
- Java
- PHP